Marguerite Higgins Papers
Marguerite Higgins Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Schulz, Bob, See White House: Eisenhower Administration
  - Scott, Hugh (Senator) (Box 12)
  - Scott Paper, Inc., See McCabe, Ralph (Scott Paper, Inc.)
  - Seib, Charles, See Evening Star (Washington, D.C.)
  - Shapiro, S. O., See Look Magazine
  - Shepherd, Lemuel C. Jr. (General) (Box 12)
  - Shriver, Robert Sargent Jr. (Box 12)
  - Sidey, Hugh, See Time Magazine Inc.
  - Sign (magazine) (Box 12)
  - Sihanouk, Norodom (Prime Minister) (Box 12)
  - Skouras, Sprous (studio executive), See Twentieth-Century-Fox
  - "Small World" (CBS) (Box 12)
  - Smith, Margaret Chase (Senator) (Box 12)
  - Sommers, Martin, See Saturday Evening Post
  - Southeast Asia (Box 12)
  - Soviet Embassy (U.S.) (Box 12)
  - Soviet Union, 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Spanish Embassy (U.S.) (Box 13)
  - Spartansburg Herald (Box 13)
  - Spencer, George (Box 13)
  - Spivak, Lawrence (talk show host), See "Meet the Press" (NBC)
  - Springer, Axel, See Die Welt
  - STAMATS Publishing Company (Box 13)
  - Stassen, Harold E. (Box 13)
  - State Historical Society of Wisconsin (Box 13)
  - Sterling, Dr. Carlos Marquez, See Free Cuba Patriotic Movement
  - Stoneman, William H. (Box 13)
  - Storch, Otto, See McCalls
  - Struwe, Ewald, See Neue Illustrierte (New Illustrated)
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays, See New York Times
  - Sulzberger, C. L., See New York Times
  - Supreme Headquarters of the Allied Powers of Europe (SHAPE) (Box 13)
  - Switzerland, See Legation of Switzerland (U.S.)
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard (Box 13)
  - Symington, Stuart (Senator) (Box 13)
  - Syracuse University (Box 13)
  - T (Box 13)
  - Taft, Robert A. (Senator) (Box 13)
  - Tanganyika, See Tanzania (United Republic of)
  - Taiwan (Box 13)
  - Tanzania (United Republic of) (Box 13)
    See also U.S. Embassy (Tanzania)
  - Taylor, Maxwell D. (General) (Box 13)
  - Ted Bates and Company (Box 13)
  - Television and radio appearances fan mail (Box 13)
    See also name of network; name of show
  - Thailand (Box 13)
  - Thayer, Mary V.R. (Mrs. Sigourney) (Box 13)
  - Thayer, Walter, See New York Herald Tribune
  - Thich Duc Nhiep (Rev.) (Box 13)
  - Thich Tri Quang (Box 13)
    O'Connor, Patrick (Fr.)
    Vietnam - Buddhists
  - This Week (magazine) (Box 13)
    See also "Youth Want to Know" (NBC)
  - Thomas, Evan, See Harper & Row Publishers
  - Thomas, Lowell ("Cinerama") (Box 13)
    See also International Platform Association
  - Thompson, Dorothy (Box 13)
  - Thuan (Msgr.) (Box 13)
  - Time (Box 13)
  - Time Magazine, Inc. (Box 13)
  - Times Picayune (New Orleans) (Box 13)
  - Tobé, See Fashion Division Federation (New York)
  - Tocsin (Box 13)
    See also Left Wing Politics; University of California, Berkeley
  - "Today" (NBC) (Box 13)
  - Townley, Updike, Carter and Rodgers (attorneys) (Box 13)
  - Tran Thien Khiem (Ambassador), See Vietnamese Embassy (U.S.)
  - Tran Van Chuong (Ambassador) (Box 13)
    See also Ngo Dinh Nhu, Madame
  - Tran Van Chuong, Madame (Box 13)
  - Tran Van Huong (Prime Minister) (Box 13)
  - Trans World Airlines (TWA) (Box 13)
  - Travall, Janet (Dr.) (MH's doctor) (Box 13)
  - Truman, Harry S., See White House: Truman Administration
  - Turagay, Seyfi (Box 13)
  - Turkish Information Office (Box 13)
  - Turnure, Pamela, See White House: Kennedy Administration
  - Twentieth-Century-Fox (Box 13)
  - U (Box 13)
  - United Nations (Box 13)
  - University of California, Berkeley (Box 13)
    See also Left Wing Politics; Tocsin
  - U.S. Air Force (Box 14)
    See also under name of person
  - U.S. Central Intelligence Agency (Box 14)
  - U.S. Congress (Box 14)
    See also under names of specific congressmen
  - U.S. Congress - National Defense and Security (Box 14)
  - U.S. Consulate (Hong Kong) (Box 14)
  - U.S. Department of Commerce (Box 14)
  - U.S. Department of Defense, 4 folders (Box 14)
  - U.S. Department of State
    - Backgrounder: Herter, Christian (Box 14)
    - Backgrounder: Rusk, Dean (Box 14)
    - Correspondence See also under name of person (Box 14)
    - Notes (Box 14)
  - U.S. Department of the Army (Box 15)
  - U.S. Department of the Navy (Box 15)
  - U.S. Department of the Treasury (Box 15)
  - U.S. Economy (Box 15)
  - U.S. Embassy (Egypt) (Box 15)
  - U.S. Embassy (France) (Box 15)
  - U.S. Embassy (Great Britain) (Box 15)
  - U.S. Embassy (India and Nepal) (Box 15)
    See also Bowles, Chester (Ambassador)
  - U.S. Embassy (Indonesia) (Box 15)
  - U.S. Embassy (Iran) (Box 15)
  - U.S. Embassy (Japan), See Murphy, Robert D. (Ambassador/executive)
  - U.S. Embassy (Soviet Union) (Box 15)
  - U.S. Embassy (Taiwan) (Box 15)
  - U.S. Embassy (Tanzania) (Box 15)
  - U.S. Embassy (Vietnam), See: Heath, Donald R. (Ambassador) Lodge, Henry Cabot Jr. (Ambassador) Nolting, Frederick E. Jr. (Ambassador) Vietnamese Embassy (U.S.)
  - U.S. Information Agency (Box 15)
  - U.S. Marine Corps, See under name of person
  - U.S. Mission to the United Nations (Box 15)
    See also Lodge, Henry Cabot Jr. (Ambassador)
  - U.S. News & World Report (Box 15)
  - U.S. Politics (Box 15)
    See also Left Wing Politics
  - U.S. Senate (Box 15)
    See also under name of Senator
  - U.S. Space Program (Box 15)
    See also NASA; Soviet Union
  - V (Box 15)
  - Valenti, Jack, See White House: Johnson Administration
  - Van Doren, Irita, See New York Herald Tribune
  - Van Fleet, James A. (General) (Box 15)
  - V.E. Friedman Associates (advertising firm) (Box 15)
  - Venezuela (Box 15)
  - Viet Cong (Box 15)
  - Vietnam
    - Buddhists (Box 15)
    - Clippings
      - Mar.-Dec. 1963, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - 1964 (Box 15)
      - 1965 (Box 16)
      - Undated (Box 16)
      - Chicago Daily News (Box 16)
      - Christian Science Monitor (Box 16)
      - New York Times, 1964
        - General, 6 folders (Box 16, 17)
        - Religion (Box 17)
        - Letters to the Editor (Box 17)
        - Editorials (Box 17)
      - New York Times, Oct.-Dec. 1965; 3 folders (Box 17)
      - Saigon Post (Box 17)
    - Provinces (Box 17)
    - Publications (in English) (Box 17)
    - Publications (in French and Vietnamese) (Box 17)
    - Reports and Studies (Box 18)
    - War Protests, See Left Wing Politics; Tocsin; University of California, Berkeley
  - Vietnam Day Committee, See Left Wing Politics; Tocsin; University of California, Berkeley
  - Vietnamese Embassy (U.S.) (Box 18)
    See also Tran Van Chuong (Ambassador)
  - "Views of the Press" (WCBS) (Box 18)
  - Voice of America (Box 18)
  - W (Box 18)
  - W. Colston Leigh, Inc. (Box 18)
    Brown, Cross & Hamilton
    Friedman, Abraham
    Gale, Bernays, Falk & Eisner
    Glasgow, Robert H.
  - Wald, Richard, See New York Herald Tribune
  - Walker, Everett, See New York Herald Tribune (Box 18)
  - Walters, Raymond Jr., See Saturday Review
  - Wanger, Walter F. (producer), See Allied Artists
  - Warner Brothers Company (Bridgeport, CT) (Box 18)
  - Warner, James E., See New York Herald Tribune
  - Warren, Earl (Governor) (Box 18)
  - Washington Evening Star, See Evening Star (Washington, D.C.)
  - Washington Post (Box 18)
    See also Bradlee, Benjamin C.
  - Wassermann, Lew (studio executive), See MCA; Paramount Studios
  - Watson, W. Marvin, See White House: Johnson Administration
  - WBBM (Chicago), See "At Random" (WBBM)
  - WCBS, See "Views of the Press" (WCBS)
  - Webb, James E., See NASA
  - Wedemeyer, Albert C. (General) (Box 18)
  - Die Welt (Box 18)
  - Die Welt am Sonntag (Box 18)
  - West, Felton, See Houston Post
  - West, Morris L. (Box 18)
  - Westmoreland, William C. (General) (Box 18)
  - White House, Eisenhower Administration (Box 18)
    See also under name of Department
  - White House, Johnson Administration (Box 18)
    - Backgrounder: 1964 (Box 18)
    - Backgrounder: 1965 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence (Box 19)
    - Humphrey, Hubert H. (Box 19)
    - Ladybird Johnson (Box 19)
      See also Carpenter, Liz
    - News Conferences & Press Releases (Box 19)
  - White House, Kennedy Administration
    See also under name of Department; Kennedy, Jackie
    - Backgrounder: Holborn, Fred (Box 19)
    - Backgrounder: Kennedy, Ted (Box 19)
    - Correspondence (Box 19)
    - News Conferences (Box 19)
  - White House, Truman Administration (Box 19)
  - White, Robert M., See New York Herald Tribune
  - Whitehead, Don, See New York Herald Tribune
  - Whitney, Courtney (Major General) (Box 19)
  - Whitney, John Hay (Jock), See New York Herald Tribune
  - Wiggins, James Russell, See Washington Post
  - Wiley, Alexander (Senator) (Box 19)
  - William Esty Company (advertising firm) (Box 19)
  - Wilson, Charles Erwin, See U.S. Department of Defense
  - Woestendick, William J., See Houston Post; Newsday
  - Women's National Press Club (Washington, D.C.) (Box 19)
  - WOR-TV, See "Ladies of the Press" (WOR-TV)
  - Wright, Jerauld (Ambassador), See U.S. Embassy (Taiwan)
  - WXIX (Milwaukee), See "Milwaukee Reports" (WXIX)
  - Y (Box 19)
  - Yockey, Harry, See Daily Reporter (Dover, OH)
  - You Chan Yang, See Korean Embassy (U.S.)
  - "Youth Wants to Know" (NBC) (Box 19)
  - Yugoslavia (Box 19)
  - Yugoslavia (U.N. Delegation to) (Box 19)
  - Z (Box 19)
  - Zablocki, Clement J. (Congressman) (Box 19)
  - Zanzibar, See Tanzania (United Republic of)
  - Zephirim, Mauclair (Ambassador) (Box 19)
  - Unidentified (Box 19)
  - Unidentified wedding congratulations (Box 19)
- Writings
  - Books
    - Jessie Benton Fremont (North Star Books, Houghton Mifflin Company), drafts; 2 folders (Box 21)
    - News is a Singular Thing (Doubleday), drafts and galley proofs; 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Our Vietnam Nightmare (Harper & Row)
      - Drafts, 50 folders total
        - Prologue and Chapters I-III, 10 folders (Box 22)
        - Chapters IV-VI, 8 folders (Box 23)
        - Chapters VII-IX, 9 folders (Box 24)
        - Chapter X-XII, 10 folders (Box 25)
        - Chapter XIII, 6 folders (Box 26)
        - Chapter XIV, 7 folders (Box 26, 27)
      - Typescripts, Chapters I-XIII; 3 folders (Box 27)
      - Galley proofs, 3 folders (Box 28)
    - Overtime in Heaven, typescript and galley proofs; 10 folders (Box 29, 30)
    - Red Plush and Black Bread (Doubleday), drafts and galley proofs (in poor condition) (Box 20)
    - War in Korea (Doubleday), drafts and galley proofs; 4 folders (Box 30)
    - Unpublished: Young John Kennedy (Houghton Mifflin) (Box 30)
  - Articles (Journals)
    - America Magazine, "Saigon summary", Jan. 4, 1964; clipping (Box 31)
    - America Magazine, "Ugly Americans in Vietnam", Oct. 3, 1964; drafts and final (Box 31)
    - The American Weekly, "The mysterious Mrs. Rhee", Sept. 13, 1953; clipping (Box 31)
    - Cosmopolitan, "China-rewrite, ", Jan. 7, 1964; galley one (Box 31)
    - The Diplomat, "The charmed life of Henry Cabot Lodge", Dec. 1965; draft, clipping (Box 31)
    - The Instructor, editorial, undated; draft (Box 31)
    - Mademoiselle, "Paris - heartbreak and hope", undated; clipping (Box 31)
    - McCalls, "How to bring up a president", undated; draft (Box 31)
    - McCalls, "Once a caesarean always a caesarean", undated; draft (Box 31)
    - National Education Association Journal, " The American foreign service - from striped pants to wash 'n wear", undated; draft (Box 31)
    - Reader's Digest, "Our secret allies - the people of East Germany", Oct. 1961; draft (Box 31)
    - Report Magazine, The chaos of Vietnam", Dec. 1964; clipping (Box 31)
    - Report Magazine, " What we lost in losing Vietnam's Diem", Oct. 1965; clipping (Box 31)
    - Saturday Evening Post, " The night raiders of Berlin", Jun. 17, 1950; clipping (Box 31)
    - Stern, "Wie uns die Anderen sehen", Jul. 1961; clipping (Box 31)
      See Box 47 for original
  - Articles (journals) - drafts
    - "Are we still underestimating Soviet Power?", undated (Box 31)
    - "Career in Crisis", undated (Box 31)
    - "Death of a Man," (Ngo Dinh Diem) (Box 31)
    - "He's taking the starch out of protocol," [Angier Biddle Duke], undated (Box 31)
    - "Is Russia fooling the U.S.A.?", undated (Box 31)
    - "My favorite Kennedy", undated (Box 31)
    - "Peril in the Philippines", undated; interview with William S.B. Lacy, U.S. Minister in the Philippines (Box 31)
    - "Red China '1964' ", undated (Box 31)
    - "They call it a vacation," [Kennedys], undated (Box 31)
    - "Vietnam - or how to be an enemy to your friends", undated (Box 31)
    - Untitled eye-witness essay about Korean War front, undated (Box 31)
  - Articles (journals) - with Peter Lisagor
    - The Diplomat, "Of skeptics and converts", Jul.-Aug. 1964; clipping (Box 31)
    - Saturday Evening Post," Every day is ladies day in Washington", undated; drafts (Box 31)
    - "RSVP - The White House", undated; draft (Box 31)
  - Articles (newspapers)
    - Chicago Daily News, 1964-1965; clippings (Box 32)
    - Chicago Sun-Times, 1959-1963; clippings (Box 32)
    - Evening Star (Washington, D.C.), 1964-1965; clippings (Box 32)
    - New York Herald Tribune
      - Drafts
        - 1953, from Japan (Box 32)
        - 1962, John F. Kennedy (Box 32)
        - 1963 (Box 32)
        - 1963, Jul.-Aug., interview with Ngo Dinh Nhu (Box 32)
        - 1964, Greece (Box 32)
        - undated, Africa, Buddhist monks, Robert F. Kennedy, Korean War POWs, interview with Madame Ngo Dinh Nhu, Vietnam, 8 folders (Box 32)
      - Galley proofs, undated (Box 32)
      - Clipping and by-line files
        - 1950, May-Jul., 2 folders (Box 32)
        - 1950, Aug.-Dec., 2 folders (Box 33)
        - 1952, Sept.-Oct. (Box 33)
        - 1952, Oct.-Nov., interview with Prime Minister Mohammed Mossadegh (Box 33)
        - 1952, Oct. 5, "These men surprised me" (This Week Magazine), interviews with Nehru, Mossadegh, the King of Siam, the Shah of Iran, Gen. Chuikov, Gen. MacArthur (Box 33)
        - 1953 (Box 33)
        - 1953, syndicated articles on Earl Browder (Box 33)
        - 1953, Apr., interview with Major General Naguib (Egypt) (This Week Magazine) (Box 33)
        - 1953, Apr. 12, "They'll never love the U.S.A!" (Box 33)
          Original is in Box 47.
        - 1953, Apr., interview with Jean Letourneau, French Minister (Box 33)
        - 1953, Apr.-May, Cold War Series (Box 33)
        - 1953, May 24, "Let's stop underestimating Soviet strength" (This Week Magazine) (Box 33)
        - 1953, Jun.-Sept., interview with Syngman Rhee, President of South Korea (series) (Box 33)
        - 1953, Jul., series on Nationalist Chinese Guerillas (Box 33)
        - 1953, Aug., series on Communist China (Box 33)
        - 1953, Sept., interview with General Mark W. Clark (Box 33)
        - 1953, Sept., series on trip to Korea, Japan, Formosa, Hong Kong, Indo-China (Box 33)
        - 1953, Dec., series on tour of Russia (Box 33)
        - 1956 (Box 33)
        - 1960, 2 folders (Box 33)
        - 1960, series on Africa (Box 33)
        - 1960, Dec. 12, Kennedy family (Box 33)
        - 1961, Jan.-Aug., 6 folders (Box 33)
        - 1961, Sept.- Dec., 2 folders (Box 34)
        - 1961, Mar., interview with Antoine Gizenga (Congo) (Box 34)
        - 1961, letters to the editor (Box 34)
        - 1962, Jan.-Dec., 6 folders (Box 34)
        - 1962, Feb.-Oct., letters to the editor (Box 34)
        - 1963, 3 folders (Box 34)
        - 1963, Aug.-Sept., series on Vietnam, 2 folders (Box 34)
        - 1963, Aug.-Sept., series on Vietnam, letters to the editor (Box 34)
        - 1965 (Box 34)
        - Undated (Box 34)
        - Syndicated Newsday articles appearing in the NYHT (Box 34)
    - Newsday columns
      - "Inside Washington"
        - Drafts, 1964 (Box 35)
        - Press releases, 1964 (Box 35)
      - "On the Spot"
        - Drafts
          - 1964, 3 folders (Box 35)
          - 1964Vietnam (Box 35)
          - 1964, Mar., Civil Rights (Box 35)
          - 1964, Sept., Buddhism (Box 35)
          - 1965 (Box 35)
          - 1965 India trip (Box 36)
          - 1965, MaySanto Domingo (Box 36)
          - 1965Vietnam trip, 2 folders (Box 36)
          - 1965 University of California, Berkeley (Box 36)
          - undatedKashmir/miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 36)
        - Press releases
          - 1963 (Box 36)
          - 1964, Jan.-Oct., 3 folders (Box 36)
          - 1964, Nov.-Dec. (Box 37)
          - 1965, Jan.-May, 5 folders (Box 37)
          - 1965, Jun.-Oct., 5 folders (Box 38)
          - 1965, Nov.-Dec., 2 folders (Box 39)
          - undated (Box 39)
        - Clippings, 1963-1965; undated; 10 folders (Box 39)
      - General articles, 1964-1965; clippings (Box 39)
      - Reports, Nov. 1963; draft/clipping, interview with W. German Chancellor Konrad Adenauer (Box 39)
      - Syndicated, 1964-1965; miscellaneous, clippings (Box 39)
    - Oakland Tribune, 1964-1965; clippings (Box 40)
    - Park East (New York), 1964, Feb. 20; clipping (Box 40)
    - Philadelphia Inquirer, 1964-1965; clippings (Box 40)
    - St. Louis Post-Dispatch, 1953-1954; clippings (Box 40)
    - Washington Post, 1950, Jun.-Dec.; clippings (Box 40)
    - Die Welt
      - Drafts
        - 1964, 2 folders (Box 40)
        - 1965, 2 folders (Box 40)
        - undated (Box 40)
      - Clippings, 1962-1965 (Box 40)
  - Diaries
    - [1 volume], includes quotes, questions and references to Seoul, Taejon, and Puson, Korea; also includes entries about being a woman correspondent; Lt. Gen. Hall (Box 41)
  - Notebooks
    - [Notebooks 1-17], undated (Box 41)
    - [Notebooks 18-29], undated (Box 42)
  - Notes (handwritten) (Box 43)
    - General, 12 folders (Box 43)
    - Interview with Sen. Hubert H. Humphrey, undated (Box 43)
    - Interview (unknown); death of President Diem, undated (Box 43)
    - Questions for interview with Jackie Kennedy, undated (Box 43)
    - Memo of conversation with Robert F. Kennedy, Nov. 2, 1962 (Box 43)
    - Westmoreland trip and briefing, undated; 1965 (Box 43)
  - Reviews
    - Higgins' review (clipping) of Morris L. West's book The Ambassador, in The Sign, May 1965 (Box 43)
  - Unidentified
    - Drafts, L'Annam D'Autrefois (in French) (Box 43)
- Memorabilia
  - Awards and certificates
    - Miscellaneous, 1951; 1953,; 1963 (Box 44)
      Includes Pulitzer Prize certificate for distinguished reporting of international affairs (1951), Long Island University Polk Memorial Award for outstanding foreign reporting (1953), Columbia University School of Journalism's 50th anniversary medal (1963), among others
    - Miscellaneous, 1951; 1959,; 1965 (Box 47)
      Veterans of Foreign Wars (1951); Vice-president’s "Kitchen Cabinet" (1959); Honorary Citizen of Dallas, TX (1965); Honor from the Free Cuba Patriotic Movement (1965); Honorary Doctorate
    - George Polk Memorial Award (Overseas Press Club of America), 1950 (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous, 1952; 1953 (Box 49)
      Distinguished Service Award, National Federation of Business and Professional Women’s Clubs, Inc. (1952); George Polk Award, Long Island University Department of Journalism (1953)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956; 1957 (Box 50)
      Women of Achievement Award, American Federation of Soroptimist Clubs, Inc. (1956); Annual Award, Philadelphia Section of the National Council of Jewish Women (1957)
  - Biographical
    - Articles/editorials, 1946; 1950-1965,; undated; 5 folders (Box 44)
    - "Higgins Correspondent" (limerick), undated (Box 44)
    - Chronologies, birth to 1953 (Box 44)
    - Obituaries and remembrances, 1966-1986 (Box 44)
    - Wedding Announcements, 1952; clippings (Box 44)
      See also Scrapbook No. 8
  - Financial and legal (Box 45)
    - Contracts (Box 45)
      - Adler, Paul F., 1953 (Box 45)
      - Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1951; 1960 (Box 45)
      - Harper & Row Publishers, 1965 (Box 45)
      - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1962 (Box 45)
      - J. Leo Kolb Company, Inc., 1954 (Box 45)
      - Keedick Lecture Bureau, Inc., 1953-1965 (Box 45)
      - New York Herald Tribune, 1959 (Box 45)
    - Employment Records, 1953-1954 (Box 45)
    - Expense accounts, New York Herald Tribune, 1951-1961; undated; 3 folders (Box 45)
    - Foreign money (Box 45)
    - Hall, Lawrence D., 1952 (Box 45)
    - Identification cards, 1953-1966 (Box 45)
    - Income taxes, 1951; 1953-1954; 3 folders (Box 45)
    - Leases, 1953 (Box 45)
    - Personal
      - 1951-1954, 3 folders (Box 45)
      - 1959-1965 (Box 45)
      - Undated (Box 45)
    - Round Hill Development, Inc., 1953 (Box 45)
    - Travel documents and letters, 1953-1965 (Box 45)
  - Photographs
    - Family and personal, undated; informal photos of Higgins and others from childhood through graduation from the Anna Head School in Berkeley, CA; Higgins in unidentified locations; 2 folders (Box 46)
    - Family (oversize), Higgins as an infant with father, Lawrence D. Higgins (accession M03-43) (Box 47)
    - Professional and social, 10 folders
      - Portraits, undated (Box 46)
      - Appearances, 1951-1953; includes Higgins at a Women's Home Companion luncheon; with Bennett Cerf and Mike Land. (Box 46)
      - Social, undated; Higgins at a party; dining with others (Box 46)
      - Hollywood, undated; Higgins with actors William Powell and Betty Grable (Box 46)
    - Trips Abroad, 12 folders
      - Cambodia, undated (Box 46)
        Includes Higgins being met at the airport; with Prince Sihanouk in the Palais Khemarin; at a banquet hosted by General Nhiek Tianlong, Cambodian Chief of Staff.
      - Egypt, undated (Box 46)
        Higgins with military leaders on the plane and at airport.
      - Korea, 1950 (Box 46)
        Several well annotated scenes from the front lines of soldiers and Higgins with others at her typewriter, airport, in front of jeep; includes photos taken by Carl Mydans of Life Magazine and the U.S. Army; many appear in Higgins' book, War in Korea.
      - Soviet Union, 1954-1955 (Box 46)
        From Higgins tour; many appear in her book, Red Plush and Black Bread.
      - Vietnam, undated (Box 46)
        Photos of Vietnamese and U.S. military and civilians including Higgins (a few are annotated in Vietnamese).
    - University of California, Berkeley protests
      - Fall Free Speech Movement (FSM) rally; several participants identified., 1964, November (Box 46)
      - Protest at Sproul Hall; several participants identified., 1964, December (Box 46)
      - Vietnam Day Committee (VDC) troop train demonstration; several participants identified, 1965, August (Box 46)
      - Undated, includes a "Get out of Vietnam March" from Berkeley to the draft board office; Selma protest march; several participants identified. (Box 46)
    - Individuals, 7 folders
      - Baruch, Bernard M. (with Higgins on a French ship, signed), 1957 (Box 46)
      - Clay, Lucius D. (General) (signed), undated (Box 46)
      - Crittenberger, Willis D. (General), 1952; with Higgins and Lt. Gen. Hall, annotated U.S. Army photograph (Box 46)
      - Johnson, Ladybird, undated; giving a tour with Higgins in attendance (Box 46)
      - MacArthur, Douglas (General), undated; With President Syngman Rhee; aboard his plane with Brig. Gen. Courtney Whitney, includes photos taken by Carl Mydans. (Box 46)
      - Rusk, Dean, undated; with Higgins and unidentified other, signed (Box 46)
      - Walker, Walton (Lt. General), 1950; undated; with Gen. William F. Dean; crossing the Kunho River; photos taken by Carl Mydans. (Box 46)
    - Oversize (Box 47)
      President Johnson (signed); Higgins with President Johnson (signed); Dr. Mohammed Mossadegh of Iran (signed); group photo of Higgins with others (unidentified) in Korea; 1 unidentified (signed).
    - Unidentified - Higgins and Lt. Gen. Hall with others, undated-1965 (Box 46)
  - Negatives
    - Miscellaneous, mostly second-generation negatives for Family, Personal, Portraits, Egypt, Korea (above) (Box 46)
      See also oversized photographs
  - Publicity
    - Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1964 (Box 44)
    - Harper & Row Publishers, 1965 (Box 44)